epicduel.com 2015-06-02

# Artix.com Privacy Policy

## REVISED June 13, 2013

**Artix Entertainment LLC** provides family friendly entertainment to our users. We are committed to protecting the safety and security of its online visitors and are sensitive to our user's concerns about the safety of personal information provided to us. We encourage all our users to read this Privacy Statement carefully in order to understand how any personal information collected about you is used. ****

This privacy statement covers the Web Sites:[www.battleon.com](http://www.battleon.com/), [www.dragonfable.com](http://www.dragonfable.com/), [www.mechquest.com](http://www.mechquest.com/), [www.herosmash.com](http://www.herosmash.com/), www.artix.com, [www.epicduel.com](http://www.epicduel.com/), [www.aq3d.com](http://www.aq3d.com/), [www.ebilgames.com](http://www.ebilgames.com/) and [www.aq.com](http://www.aq.com/). Because these Web Sites want to demonstrate their commitment to your privacy, they have agreed to disclose their information practices and have their privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. 

We are also aware, that due to our content we may have some younger users on our site. We recognize the need to provide additional protection to those younger users. The Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act ('COPPA') requires that we inform parents and legal guardians about how we collect, use, and disclose personal information from children under 13 years of age. We explain this information under the Children’s Privacy Policy section below.

Information You Provide to Us And How We Use This Information  
What We WILL NOT DO With the Information You Provide to Us  
What Are Cookies?  
What Are IP Addresses?  
Message Boards  
Mobile  
Security and Credit Card Use  
CHILDRENS’S PRIVACY POLICY  
Revision Information  
Contacting Artix Entertainment

Information You Provide to Us And How We Use This Information

**Chat Logs of Users**  
Artix Entertainment creates and retains logs of all chat conversations (both private and public) between users ('Chat Content'), as well as private game play patterns and other activity of users within Company games. Additionally, you acknowledge and grant permission to Company to review, monitor, disclose, censor, delete or otherwise remove Chat Content and other private user activity within Company games for the purpose of preventing breaches of this Agreement and of other Company prohibitions on unlawful or abusive activity. Accordingly, you acknowledge that you have no privacy rights whatsoever in Chat Content or any other content that you create in Company games.

**Free Accounts**  
Artix Entertainment has a large portion of their games available to the users for free. In order to register a character for the free version of the game, the only information that Artix Entertainment collects is the user’s e-mail address if the user is over 13 years of age. The e-mail address is used for the following purposes:

  1. To send a confirmation notice to the user of their character registration and password information.
  2. Upon the user’s request, to send the user password information when the user has lost or forgotten the password.
  3. In response to any question, concerns or problem that the user contacted Artix Entertainment about.
  4. To contact the user about any problem with the user’s account or conduct in the game.
  5. To send out a newsletter*. Out of respect for your privacy, we provide a way to unsubscribe. Please see the Choice and Opt-out section below.

* Artix Entertainment games are unique in a sense that we design and run numerous special events that keep the game constantly fresh, challenging, fun and interesting for our users. Some of these events coincide with actual real life holidays, such as Valentine’s Day, other events are made up as we go along. We use the newsletter to notify our users of all the current events, changes, improvements, upgrades, new characters, etc. In addition, occasionally we may notify our users of new products and services that Artix Entertainment has designed and made available exclusively to our users. In addition, Artix Entertainment may send promotional items and advertisements from the sponsors, however Artix Entertainment will not divulge your personal information to the sponsor directly.

By registering for Artix Entertainment, you consent to: a) receive periodic email communications from Artix Entertainment concerning your account; and b) receive the above-described email newsletter.

**Choice/Opt-Out**  
If you no longer wish to receive our email newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in any newsletter email message. We also offer an opportunity to opt-out of certain communications on our Manage Account web pages, or you may contact us at (813) 774-8493, or use the email or physical address listed below to opt-out.

**Subscriber Accounts**  
A Subscriber Account is a paid membership account that provides our users with additional access and privileges while playing Artix Entertainment. The Subscriber Account requires and uses all of the information listed under the Free Account in the same manner. In addition to the above, however, we will require you to provide the following information:

  1. First and last name
  2. Address, city, state and zip code
  3. Home telephone number

We are copied with this information by PayPal (see Security and Credit Card Use below) and require this information for the sole purpose of verifying your account and payment information.

**What We WILL DO With Your Personal Information**  
We use third-party service providers (“Service Providers”), such as a shipping company to fulfill orders, and a credit card processing company to bill you for goods and services. When you sign up with the website, we will provide your personal information (e.g. name, address, phone number and email address) to Service Providers as necessary for such Service Providers to provide their respective services. Service Providers to whom Artix Entertainment discloses your personal information all have agreed to abide by this Privacy Policy, and Service Providers are specifically prohibited from using your personal information for promotional purposes. Please note that Service Providers (e.g., PayPal)may have separate privacy policies that govern their collection, use and storage of information that you provide to them directly.

**What We WILL NOT DO With Your Personal Information**  
Artix Entertainment is supported by its Subscriber Account Users. Therefore Artix Entertainment does not share, sell, rent or trade your or your child's personally identifiable information with any third parties for their promotional purposes. We reserve the right to disclose your or your child's personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web Sites.

**Other Provisions**  
**What Are Cookies?**  
A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. Each cookie can only be accessed by the web site that created the cookie. We use cookies on this site. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site.

We use both temporary session ID cookies and persistent cookies. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate on our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your web browser's help information.

We set persistent cookies to store your game account login and/or password, so you don't have to enter it more than once. Persistent cookies also enable us to detect new users, and track referals to the site to reward users that refer their friends to the site.

If your browser rejects all cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site including purchasing membership, will be limited.

**Third Party Tracking Technologies**  
Third party partners, affiliates, and advertisers employ a software technology called Web beacons, that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Web beacons are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, Web beacons are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence.

The use of cookies and Web beacon by our partners, affiliates, and advertisers is not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these tracking technologies. Our partners use persistant cookies and Web beacons to track users that visit our site through their advertising networks. For more information on cookies, please visit the **Federal Trade Commission's** website at <http://www.ftc.gov/ftc/cookies.shtm>.

**Flash LSOs**  
We use local shared objects, also known as Flash cookies, to store your preferences such as volume control or high game score, or display content based upon what you view on our site to personalize your visit.  Third Parties, with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity, use Flash cookies to collect and store information. Flash cookies are different from browser cookies because of the amount of, type of, and how data is stored.  Cookie management tools provided by your browser will not remove Flash cookies. To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies click [here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118).

**What are IP Addresses?**  
An IP address (Internet Protocol address) is a unique address that certain electronic devices use in order to identify and communicate with each other on a computer network utilizing the Internet Protocol standard (IP)—in simpler terms, a computer address. Any participating network device—including routers, computers, time-servers, printers, Internet fax machines, and some telephones—can have their own unique address.

**Message Boards**  
If you use a message board or forum on this Web Site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums.

The message board must be signed up for separately from the game and is subject to TERMS OF USE. To request removal of your personal information from our message board or forums, contact us at . In some cases we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**Mobile**  
Artix Entertainment may use tools or third party analytical software to collect and use certain non-personal data that does not enable Artix Entertainment to identify you. The types of non-personal data Artix Entertainment may collect and use include, but are not limited to: (i) mobile device type and device properties; (ii) mobile device software platform and firmware; (iii) mobile phone carrier; (iv) geographical data no more accurate that metropolitan areas; (v) gamescore and achievements; (vi) other non-personal data as reasonably required by Artix Entertainment to enhance its services.

Artix Entertainment may use the collected data for purposes of analyzing usage of Artix Entertainment games, managing and providing Artix Entertainment games and to further develop Artix Entertainment’s services and products. Artix Entertainment reserves the right to use and disclose the collected non-personal data for purposes of advertisement by Artix Entertainment or Artix Entertainment’s partners.

**Security and Credit Card Use**  
The security of your personal information is important to us and our third party vendors. When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number, Corp ID number or ABN) on our site or an affiliate sign up page, registration or order forms, both Artix Entertainment and our third party vendors encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). 

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personally identifiable information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.   
If you have any questions about the security of our website, you can email us at: 

Artix Entertainment utilizes a credit card processor to process your payments while on our site. We share your name, email address and credit card information with these third parties to provide the service requested. These third parties are not permitted to use your information for their own promotional purposes. Alternatively you have the option to use the payment options listed below. The personal information (such as name and email address, but non inclusive of your financial information) collected by these third parties is shared back with Artix Entertainment for the purpose of fulfilling your subscription request. 

**PayPal**  
Founded in 1998, PayPal, an eBay Company, enables any individual or business with an email address to securely, easily and quickly send and receive payments online. To find our more about PayPal and its privacy and security policies, please visit [www.paypal.com](http://www.paypal.com/). PayPal is our preferred method of payment. 

**PlaySpan**  
Founded in 1998, PlaySpan offers over 100 methods of payment, including cash and money order methods (additional fees may apply). To find out more about PlaySpan and its privacy and security policies, please visit [www.playspan.com](http://www.playspan.com/)

**ClickAndBuy**  
Founded in 2001, ClickAndBuy enables individuals or businesses with an email address the ability to securely and easily send and receive payments online. To find out more about ClickAndBuy and its privacy and security policies, please visit [www.clickandbuy.com](http://www.clickandbuy.com/).

**Cherry Credits**  
Cherry Credits allows individuals or businesses to make payments without the dominant use of Credit Cards. To find out more about Cherry Credits and its privacy and security policies, please visit [www.cherrycredits.com](http://www.cherrycredits.com/).

**Name of Third Party Partner** | **What info is shared with partner?** | **What info is collected by this partner?** | **Partner’s purpose** | **Link to partner’s privacy policy**  
---|---|---|---|---  
PayPal | userid, email | name, address, email, payment info | Payment Provider | [PayPal Privacy Policy](https://www.paypal.com/us/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=p/gen/ua/policy_privacy-outside)  
PayPalPro | name, address, email, credit card | name, address, email, payment info | Payment Provider | [PayPal Privacy Policy](https://www.paypal.com/us/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=p/gen/ua/policy_privacy-outside)  
PlaySpan | userid, email | name, address, email, payment info | Payment Provider | [PlaySpan Privacy Policy](http://www.playspan.com/privacy/)  
FastCash Brazil | none | username, email, payment info | Payment Provider | [FastCash Brazil Privacy Policy](https://www.fastcash.com.br/en/)  
Paymentez | userid, email | payment info | Payment Provider | [Paymentez Privacy Policy](https://d3f8wu33pc6fwg.cloudfront.net/checkout/docs/privacy/pp_2013_pt-BR.pdf)  
DragonPay | userid, email | payment info | Payment Provider | [DragonPay Privacy Policy](http://www.dragonpay.ph/about/)  
cashU | userid | payment info | Payment Provider | [cashU Privacy Policy](https://www.cashu.com/site/en/privacyPolicy)  
Mobius | userid | payment info | Payment Provider | [Mobius Privacy Policy](http://drupal.jordanacosta.com/?q=node/26)  
Allopass SMS | userid | cell phone number | Payment Provider | [Allopass Privacy Policy](http://www.allopass.com/us/legal/privacy)  
Boku SMS | userid | cell phone number | Payment Provider | [Boku Privacy Policy](http://boku.com/privacy/)  
Cherry Credits | userid | payment info | Payment Provider | [Cherry Credits Privacy Policy](http://www.cherrycredits.com/sg/pages/privacy-policy)  
INCOMM | userid | none | Payment Provider | [INCOMM Privacy Policy  
](http://www.incomm.com/) (click privacy policy at bottom of page)   
Blackhawk | userid | none | Payment Provider | [Blackhawk Privacy Policy](http://www.blackhawknetwork.com/privacy-policy)  
Rixty | userid | email | Payment Provider | [Rixty Privacy Policy](https://www.rixty.com/docs/PrivacyPolicy.html)  
Zeevex | userid, email | email | Payment Provider | [Zeevex Privacy Policy](https://www.zeevex.com/privacy)  
OpenBucks | userid | none | Payment Provider | [OpenBucks Privacy Policy](http://www.openbucks.com/privacy-policy.html)  
Freecause | userid | none | Toolbar | [Freecause Privacy Policy](http://rakutenloyalty.com/legal-website-privacy-policy/)  
SuperRewards | userid, Age | optional: email, gender, birthdate | OfferWall | [SuperRewards Privacy Policy](http://www.superrewards-offers.com/super/privacy)  
Matomy Money | userid, Age | optional: email | OfferWall | [Matomy Money Privacy Policy](http://www.matomymoney.com/about/privacy-policy/)  
Peanut Labs | encrypted userid, Age | optional: age, gender, demographics, varies | OfferWall | [Peanut Labs Privacy Policy](http://www.peanutlabs.com/media/privacy_policy.php)  
Sometrics | userid | optional: email | OfferWall | [Sometrics Privacy Policy](https://www.sometrics.com/company/privacy/)  
TokenAds | userid, Age | optional: name, email, facebook connect | OfferWall | [TokenAds Privacy Policy](http://www.tokenads.com/privacy.html)  
SponsorPay | userid | optional: email, gender, birthdate | OfferWall | [SponsorPay Privacy Policy](http://sponsorpay.com/)  
SupersonicAds | userid | optional: email | OfferWall | [SupersonicAds Privacy Policy](http://www.supersonicads.com/about-us/privacy-policy)  
Volume11 Media | userid, Age | none | OfferWall | [Volumn11 Media Privacy Policy](http://v11media.com/privacy-policy/)  
RadiumOne | userid | optional: email | OfferWall | [RadiumOne Privacy Policy](http://radiumone.com/privacy-policy.html)  
Jampp | userid | optional: facebook connect | OfferWall | [Jampp](http://jampp.com/index.php)  
Shizmoo | none | none | Advertiser | [Shizmoo Privacy Policy](http://www.cpmstar.com/index.aspx?nav=privacy)  
Google | none | none | Advertiser | [Google Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)  
WildTangent | none | none | Advertiser | [Wild Tangent Privacy Policy](http://www.wildtangent.com/legal/privacy)  
WildTangent Brandboost | userid | none | Advertiser | [Wild Tangent Privacy Policy](http://www.wildtangent.com/legal/privacy)  
AdCash | userid | none | Advertiser | [AdCash Privacy Policy](https://www.adcash.com/en/privacy.php)  
Game Advertising Online | userid | none | Advertiser | [GameAdvertising Online Privacy](https://www.game-advertising-online.com/index.php?section=doc&action=privacy)  
adsmarket.com | userid | none | Advertiser | [adsmarket Privacy Policy](http://www.matomy.com/assets/global-privacy-policy)  
popmog.com | userid | none | Advertiser | [popmog Privacy Policy](http://en.popmog.com/static/privacy)  
ad2games.com | none | none | Advertiser | [ad2games Privacy Policy](http://web.ad2games.com/_launch/index.php?article_id=25&clang=1)  
ad4game.com | none | none | Advertiser | [ad4game Privacy Policy](http://ad4game.com/privacy_policy.php)  
ValueClick | none | none | Advertiser | [ValueClick Privacy Policy](http://www.valueclick.com/privacy)  
  
If you have any inquiries regarding our partner’s privacy practices or how they use your child’s personal information, please contact us directly at .

**Social Media (Features) and Widgets**  
Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

**CHILDRENS’S PRIVACY POLICY**  
Artix Entertainment encourages parents and legal guardians to spend time online with their children. We urge parents and legal guardians to instruct their children to never give out their personal information online without permission. We also recognize a special need to protect personal information obtained from children. In compliance with Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act ('COPPA'), we have adopted the following policies regarding children under the age of 13 ('Children'):

**Type and Use of Information Collected from Children**  
To create a Free Account, Artix Entertainment does not collect or require for the child to provide any personally identifiable information if the child is known to Artix Entertainment to be under the age of 13. 

To create a Subscriber Account, Artix Entertainment does require an e-mail address as well as the parent’s correct billing information as outlined under the Subscriber Accounts section. __

For Subscriber Accounts, we use your Subscriber e-mail address for the following purposes:

  1. To send a confirmation notice to the parent of their child's character registration and password information.
  2. Upon the parent’s request, to send the user password information when the child has lost or forgotten their password.
  3. In response to any questions, concerns or problems that a subscriber has contacted Artix Entertainment about.* 
  4. To contact the parent about any problem with the child’s account or conduct in the game.
  5. To send out a newsletter to the subscriber email account**.

*We recognize that young children may inadvertently give out personal information including their e-mail address when contacting us with any questions, problems, or concerns they have encountered while playing the game. We do not collect or use any such additional personal information acquired in this manner unless it is necessary for us to respond to the problem or question or concern. We reserve the right to disclose your child's personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web Sites.

** Artix Entertainment games are unique in a sense that we design and run numerous special events that keep the game constantly fresh, challenging, fun and interesting for our users. Some of these events coincide with actual real life holidays, such as Valentine’s Day, other events are made up as we go along. We use the newsletter to notify our users of all the upcoming events, changes, improvements, upgrades, new characters, etc. In addition, occasionally we may notify our users of new products and services that Artix Entertainment has designed and made available exclusively to our users.

If a child desires to upgrade his/her account to Subscriber Status, a parent or legal guardian will be required to divulge additional reasonably necessary information as described above under Subscriber Accounts. 

Artix Entertainment does not share, sell, rent or trade, your child’s personal information to any third parties for their promotional purposes.   
Artix Entertainment does not condition a child’s participation in an online activity on the child providing more personal information than is reasonably necessary for the activity. In addition, Parent’s have the right to consent to the website’s use of their child’s personal information without having to consent to its disclosure of that information to third parties. Parents may consent to the website’s use of their child’s personal information, but request that such personal information is not disclosed to third parties, by emailing us at 

**Notification and Verifiable Parental Consent**  
At this time, whenever Artix Entertainment is aware that a user is under the age of 13, Artix Entertainment requires the child submit the parent’s email address. We will then provide proper parental notice of the child’s use of the site, including their username and password. For Subscriber Accounts, the receipt of payment is considered actual, verifiable consent from the parents to the child’s use of our website and to any information that was divulged as reasonably necessary to process payments, verify and maintain the account.

**How can parents access, change or delete personally identifiable information about their children?**  
Once again, we would like to assure you that we do not keep any information other than what is listed above. However, parents are welcome to contact us about any personally identifiable information about their child by email. If your child's personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, or delete it by making the change within the 'Account Management' section of the site, or by contacting us at the email address provided below. We will respond to your request to access within 30 days. Parents may request that we discontinue collection and use of their Child's Personal Information and request that we delete it by contacting us at the email address provided below. 

**How can users acess, change or delete personally identifiable information about themselves?  
**If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update or delete it by making a change within the 'Account Management' section of the site, or by contacting us at the email address provided below. We will respond to your request to access within 30 days.

**Data Retention**  
We will retain your informationfor as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at .  We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**Revision Information**  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page. If we make material changes to how we use Personal Information collected from children under age 13, we will notify parents by email in order to obtain verifiable parental consent for the new uses of the child's Personal Information.

**Revision Information**  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page. If we make material changes to how we use Personal Information collected from children under age 13, we will notify parents by email in order to obtain verifiable parental consent for the new uses of the child's Personal Information.

**Contacting Artix Entertainment**  
If you need further assistance or have any additional questions or comments about our Privacy Policy, please contact us at  or write to us:

**Member Services**   
Artix Entertainment, LLC  
12000 North Dale Mabry Highway  
Suite 110  
Tampa, FL 33618   
For Payment Questions Only, Please Call (813) 774-8493
